Taller Martín Pescador Press Records, 1971-ongoing.
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Records of the Taller Martín Pescador Press. 1971-ongoing.
MS 353
Juan Pascoe.
Correspondence, printing production materials, chapbooks, invitations, posters, and other materials relating to, or produced by, handpress printer Juan Pascoe. Published monographs were pulled from the collection, catalogued and shelved separately.
Size of Collection
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Biographical Note
Juan Pascoe, handpress printer, was born in Chicago in 1946. His father was a Mexican diplomat with the United Nations, and his mother an American. He received most of his education in the United States. After studying English at Whitman College (BA 1969), Pascoe spent a year as a printing apprentice to Harry Duncan at the Cummington Press in West Branch Iowa (1971-1972). He moved to Mexico in 1973 and first began printing under Imprenta Rasucache, or "Shabby Press," (1973-1975), before founding the Taller Martín Pescador (Kingfisher Workshop) in 1975.
In 1987, he produced the first book reflecting his historical interest in Mexican book arts (no. 112 on checklist). Pascoe has since become known for major studies of 16th and 17th century Mexican printers. He is located in Tacámbaro, near Mexico City.
Scope and Content Note
The bulk of this collection is printing production materials of the handpress printer, Juan Pascoe. It includes his first efforts at West Branch, Iowa, 1971-1972; his initial press, Imprenta Rascuache, in Mexico, 1973-1975; and his Taller Martín Pescador in Mexico, 1975-. Materials range from calling cards and invitations to exhibition posters; from chapbooks of avant-garde poetry to folio-sized historical studies and bibliographies of Mexican printers of the 16th-18th centuries. Writers and illustrators whose work first became known through publication at the Taller Martín Pescador have since become established as major figures.
Access Terms
Pascoe, Juan.
Imprenta Rascuache -- Archives.
Taller Martín Pescador -- Archives.
Printers -- Handpresses.
Artists' books -- Mexico.
Printers -- Mexico -- 20th century.
Publishers and publishing -- Mexico.
Small presses -- Mexico.
Cummington Press.
Container List
- Series 1: Records of the Taller Martín Pescador Press, 1971-1998
  - Biographical information, Juan Pascoe (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - West Branch, 1971-1972. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Imprente Resucache, 1973-1975. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Taller Martín Pescador, 1975-1977. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Taller Martín Pescador, 1978-1979. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Taller Martín Pescador, 1980-1982. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Taller Martín Pescador, 1982-1989. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Taller Martín Pescador, 1990. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Taller Martín Pescador, 1991-1994. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Taller Martín Pescador, 1995-1996. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Taller Martín Pescador, 1997. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Taller Martín Pescador, 1998. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Imprente Resucache (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Taller Martín Pescador (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Taller Martín Pescador (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Taller Martín Pescador (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Taller Martín Pescador (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Taller Martín Pescador (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Taller Martín Pescador (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Taller Martín Pescador (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Taller Martín Pescador (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Taller Martín Pescador (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Taller Martín Pescador (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Taller Martín Pescador (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Taller Martín Pescador (Box 3)